A simple western about the origin of the American Dream.
First Cow is a drama, western film directed by Kelly Reichardt.
In the 1820s, a taciturn loner and skilled cook travels west to Oregon
Territory, where he meets a Chinese immigrant also seeking his fortune.
Soon the two team up on a dangerous scheme to steal milk from the wealthy
landowner’s prized Jersey cow—the first, and only, in the territory.
Cookie, played by John Magaro.
King-Lu, played by Orion Lee.
Chief Factor, played by Toby Jones.
Lloyd, played by Ewen Bremner.
Captain, played by Scott Shepherd.
Totillicum, played by Gary Farmer.
First Cow is a 2019 American drama film directed by Kelly Reichardt and co-written
with Jonathan Raymond, based on Raymond's 2004 novel The Half-Life.
Set in 1820s Oregon Country, it follows a traveling cook and a Chinese immigrant who
start an illicit business using milk stolen from a wealthy trader's cow.
The film stars John Magaro, Orion Lee, Toby Jones, Ewen Bremner, Lily
Gladstone, and René Auberjonois in one of his final roles.
The film premiered at the Telluride Film Festival on August 30, 2019, and competed
for the Golden Bear at the 70th Berlin International Film Festival.
It was released in the United States by A24 in March 2020,
with a wider digital release in July 2020.
First Cow received critical acclaim, winning Best Film from the New York Film Critics Circle, and was named one of the ten
best films of 2020 by the National Board of Review, as well as the third-best film of 2020 by Sight and Sound.
The film explores themes of immigrant, based on novel or
book, fur trapping, oregon, usa, 19th century.
The tone is emotional.